<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><category term="books" label="r/books"/><updated>2020-05-22T16:23:18+00:00</updated><icon>https://www.redditstatic.com/icon.png/</icon><id>/r/books.rss</id><link rel="self" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books.rss" type="application/atom+xml" /><link rel="alternate" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books" type="text/html" /><logo>https://b.thumbs.redditmedia.com/asu3_HVQEKFGKOl1CwjnrgpQqL7IcHZsmDpLqJkJJ5M.png</logo><subtitle>This is a moderated subreddit. It is our intent and purpose to foster and encourage in-depth discussion about all things related to books, authors, genres, or publishing in a safe, supportive environment. If you're looking for help with a personal book recommendation, consult our Weekly Recommendation Thread, Suggested Reading page, or ask in r/suggestmeabook.</subtitle><title>So many books, so little time</title><entry><author><name>/u/leowr</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/leowr</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12799420-prudence&quot;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;When Prudence Alessandra Maccon Akeldama (Rue to her friends) is given an unexpected dirigible, she does what any sensible female would under similar circumstances - names it the Spotted Custard and floats to India in pursuit of the perfect cup of tea. But India has more than just tea on offer. Rue stumbles upon a plot involving local dissidents, a kidnapped brigadier&amp;#39;s wife, and some awfully familiar Scottish werewolves. Faced with a dire crisis and an embarrassing lack of bloomers, what else is a young lady of good breeding to do but turn metanatural and find out everyone&amp;#39;s secrets, even thousand-year-old fuzzy ones? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;For May we will be reading Prudence by Gail Carriger. Gail will be joining us on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, May 28&lt;/strong&gt; for an AMA.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As always, the dates of and links to the discussion threads can be found in the sticky comment on this post. You are welcome to read at your own pace. Don&amp;#39;t worry about joining later on in the month. Usually it is pretty easy to catch up, but you are always welcome to join the discussions a little later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For those of you that are viewing reddit on the redesigned desktop version you will see an option on this post to &amp;#39;follow&amp;#39;. If you &amp;#39;follow&amp;#39; the book club post you will receive a notification when a new post, a discussion thread for book club, is added to the collection. It is still being tested, so it may not be perfect, but perhaps it will make it easier to join the discussions when they go up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;p.s. If you are interested in our previous selections you can find an overview &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/wiki/bookclub&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/leowr&quot;&gt; /u/leowr &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gbg0kn/the_rbooks_book_club_selection_for_may_is/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gbg0kn/the_rbooks_book_club_selection_for_may_is/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gbg0kn</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gbg0kn/the_rbooks_book_club_selection_for_may_is/" /><updated>2020-05-01T10:58:27+00:00</updated><title>The /r/books Book Club Selection for May is Prudence by Gail Carriger</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/AutoModerator</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/AutoModerator</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our weekly recommendation thread! A few years ago now the mod team decided to condense the many &amp;quot;suggest some books&amp;quot; threads into one big mega-thread, in order to consolidate the subreddit and diversify the front page a little. Since then, we have removed suggestion threads and directed their posters to this thread instead. This tradition continues, so let&amp;#39;s jump right in!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every comment in reply to this self-post must be a request for suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All suggestions made in this thread must be direct replies to other people&amp;#39;s requests. Do not post suggestions in reply to this self-post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All unrelated comments will be deleted in the interest of cleanliness.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to get the best recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most successful recommendation requests include a description of the kind of book being sought. This might be a particular kind of protagonist, setting, plot, atmosphere, theme, or subject matter. You may be looking for something similar to another book (or film, TV show, game, etc), and examples are great! Just be sure to explain &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you liked about them too. Other helpful things to think about are genre, length and reading level.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr/&gt; &lt;p&gt;All Weekly Recommendation Threads are linked below the header throughout the week to guarantee that this thread remains active day-to-day. For those bursting with books that you are hungry to suggest, the suggested sort is new; you may need to do this manually if your app or settings means this does not happen for you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If this thread has not slaked your desire for tasty book suggestions, we propose that you head on over to the aptly named subreddit &lt;a href=&quot;/r/suggestmeabook&quot;&gt;/r/suggestmeabook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;The Management&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/AutoModerator&quot;&gt; /u/AutoModerator &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gofx15/weekly_recommendation_thread_may_22_2020/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gofx15/weekly_recommendation_thread_may_22_2020/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gofx15</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gofx15/weekly_recommendation_thread_may_22_2020/" /><updated>2020-05-22T09:07:47+00:00</updated><title>Weekly Recommendation Thread: May 22, 2020</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/weeegeeee</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/weeegeeee</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;First thing I should mention is that when I read the book the first time I had read the abridged version. Having read the unabridged now, I recognize the huge difference of about 500 pages! What an incredible journey, further cemented in my mind as my favorite book and the greatest revenge story of all time. Everything is so carefully planned out and it&amp;#39;s so wonderfully satisfying when the pieces fall into place. It&amp;#39;s amazing to me how mesmerizing and relevant this book still is even after 200 years, highly highly recommended. P.S. Stay far far away from the 2002 movie, I re-watched it recently for nostalgia sake and it&amp;#39;s disgusting how much they simplified the plot into a dumb action movie. If you want an excellent adaptation that is very faithful to the book, check out an anime called Gankutsuou.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/weeegeeee&quot;&gt; /u/weeegeeee &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goeznz/just_finished_rereading_the_count_of_monte_cristo/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goeznz/just_finished_rereading_the_count_of_monte_cristo/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_goeznz</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goeznz/just_finished_rereading_the_count_of_monte_cristo/" /><updated>2020-05-22T07:47:55+00:00</updated><title>Just finished re-reading The Count of Monte Cristo and oh my goodness, what a marvelous book. It has been my favorite book since I read it in 8th or 9th grade, decided to read it again about 17 years later.</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/mrchaotica</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/mrchaotica</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/go1waq/libraries_have_never_needed_permission_to_lend/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://b.thumbs.redditmedia.com/chXJGEX5lqYP5Kj2TX0HyYr1tbbtLl5sMlTePXvtfys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Libraries Have Never Needed Permission To Lend Books, And The Move To Change That Is A Big Problem&quot; title=&quot;Libraries Have Never Needed Permission To Lend Books, And The Move To Change That Is A Big Problem&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/mrchaotica&quot;&gt; /u/mrchaotica &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20200519/13244644530/libraries-have-never-needed-permission-to-lend-books-move-to-change-that-is-big-problem.shtml&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/go1waq/libraries_have_never_needed_permission_to_lend/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</content><id>t3_go1waq</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/go1waq/libraries_have_never_needed_permission_to_lend/" /><updated>2020-05-21T18:07:04+00:00</updated><title>Libraries Have Never Needed Permission To Lend Books, And The Move To Change That Is A Big Problem</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/elkemosabe</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/elkemosabe</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year so far, I&amp;#39;ve read 36 books. This is the most I&amp;#39;ve ever read in a year by quite a long way and I&amp;#39;m loving that I&amp;#39;m back into reading so much.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;#39;ve noticed is that I&amp;#39;ve become more imaginative/having stronger dreams. But on top of that I&amp;#39;ve noticed I have much better memory when it comes to what I&amp;#39;ve read.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It used to be that I&amp;#39;d only really remember what was going on while I was reading, and I struggled to remember details of what had happened once I put a book down. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#39;m at the point where I can picture scenes in my head (previously I wasn&amp;#39;t a visualizer when I read) and just this morning I was able to recount to my girlfriend the entire plot of The Mysterious Island of Doctor Mureau which I finished yesterday. Though I still can&amp;#39;t picture faces. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I guess it doesn&amp;#39;t really seem like a big deal, but I&amp;#39;m incredibly excited about the fact that I was able to recount the plot in detail. It&amp;#39;s cool to see how reading regularly again is having a positive impact on the way I think.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/elkemosabe&quot;&gt; /u/elkemosabe &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok04c/reading_regularly_again_is_helping_my_memory_and/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok04c/reading_regularly_again_is_helping_my_memory_and/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gok04c</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok04c/reading_regularly_again_is_helping_my_memory_and/" /><updated>2020-05-22T14:08:19+00:00</updated><title>Reading regularly again is helping my memory and imagination</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/pbntm2</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/pbntm2</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m tired of people talking about tropes or things that books did badly without actually mentioning the names of the books or the authors who do this. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Half the time I&amp;#39;m left feeling like OP is probably complaining about a TV show rather than a book. Or they&amp;#39;re complaining about &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; book and making it seem like it&amp;#39;s so common, when it not. Or it&amp;#39;s about a particularly stupid genre, and then they&amp;#39;re shocked when the books in that genre are stupid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;ETA: I&amp;#39;m not going to call out posters by name, what the hell is wrong with you people. Maybe if you only sort by Hot you don&amp;#39;t see these posts, but I also sort by New, and it&amp;#39;s extremely common.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/pbntm2&quot;&gt; /u/pbntm2 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok4y2/if_youre_going_to_post_about_tropes_in_books_tell/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok4y2/if_youre_going_to_post_about_tropes_in_books_tell/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gok4y2</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok4y2/if_youre_going_to_post_about_tropes_in_books_tell/" /><updated>2020-05-22T14:16:09+00:00</updated><title>If you're going to post about tropes in books, tell us what books you've read that have these tropes</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/johnsonexe</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/johnsonexe</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the title says, I just finished the Farseer trilogy by Robin Hobb. Before starting this trilogy the last time I had read this much was probably when I was in elementary school. Since then, I&amp;#39;ve read a book here and there as well as the ones that I&amp;#39;ve been required to read throughout my schooling. However, I think these books have rekindled my love for reading. With all this quarantine stuff going on; some days I&amp;#39;d read nearly the entire day and with others at least an hour. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I had a hard time getting into the first book, Assassin&amp;#39;s Apprentice, but once I got about half way through I breezed through the rest. I wasn&amp;#39;t super invested in the series after finishing Apprentice but I still planned on reading the next two books. Royal Assassin is what really hooked me; I finished it in a little over two days (which was fast for a 700 page book at my reading speed). Royal was what got me invested in the characters, especially Verity, and after that cliffhanger ending I was obsessed. Then comes Assassin&amp;#39;s Quest, and I&amp;#39;ll be honest I had a hard time getting past the first 200ish pages. After that I started to really fly through it and it totally blew me out of the water. The plot went in many ways I had not expected it to, and I was surprisingly content with the end as I felt it was suiting for Fitz after all he had been through. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I now plan on reading the rest of Robin Hobb&amp;#39;s works and got the Liveship Traders trilogy ready to read. I&amp;#39;m excited to see what comes next to Fitz in the Tawny Man trilogy and Fitz and the Fool. I hope after finishing these books I can stay interested in reading again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/johnsonexe&quot;&gt; /u/johnsonexe &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gohthy/just_finished_the_farseer_trilogy_by_robin_hobb/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gohthy/just_finished_the_farseer_trilogy_by_robin_hobb/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gohthy</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gohthy/just_finished_the_farseer_trilogy_by_robin_hobb/" /><updated>2020-05-22T11:43:13+00:00</updated><title>Just finished the Farseer trilogy by Robin Hobb</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/NinjaDiscoJesus</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/NinjaDiscoJesus</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gofqsb/a_hardback_first_edition_harry_potter_book_which/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://b.thumbs.redditmedia.com/tN9iGRKUVGxsKPorm46c3MQopPRpw0IjhHP5N09cUaM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A hardback first edition Harry Potter book which was found in a skip has sold for £33,000 at auction.&quot; title=&quot;A hardback first edition Harry Potter book which was found in a skip has sold for £33,000 at auction.&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/NinjaDiscoJesus&quot;&gt; /u/NinjaDiscoJesus &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/amp/uk-england-derbyshire-52757703&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gofqsb/a_hardback_first_edition_harry_potter_book_which/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</content><id>t3_gofqsb</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gofqsb/a_hardback_first_edition_harry_potter_book_which/" /><updated>2020-05-22T08:52:24+00:00</updated><title>A hardback first edition Harry Potter book which was found in a skip has sold for £33,000 at auction.</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/kickbackbecool</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/kickbackbecool</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man, when I was barely getting into middle school, I&amp;#39;d always go to the library and read Cirque Du Freak over Harry Potter books. Something about it made me glue to my seat and read it for hours on end after school or during the weekend when I went to the library. I highly recommend if you like vampire stories, I&amp;#39;d HIGHLY recommend reading it even though it&amp;#39;s over 20 years old. I just randomly was googling it and brought so many teenage memories. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was always surprised nobody took the chance to read it, I always tried to get my friends to read it, but they decided to always read Harry Potter. Hope you guys give it a chance!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/kickbackbecool&quot;&gt; /u/kickbackbecool &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gnr9hj/the_cirque_du_freak_series_by_darren_shan_most/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gnr9hj/the_cirque_du_freak_series_by_darren_shan_most/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gnr9hj</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gnr9hj/the_cirque_du_freak_series_by_darren_shan_most/" /><updated>2020-05-21T05:54:32+00:00</updated><title>The Cirque du Freak series by Darren Shan (most underrated teenage book)</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/imnotthatguyiswear</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/imnotthatguyiswear</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I counted seven instances of this today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I just finished reading xxx and it was great!&amp;quot; Sometimes it just feels like they&amp;#39;re fishing for upvotes, doesn&amp;#39;t it? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I mean, come on. Give us something to discuss here. Something like &amp;quot;I love how the narrator breaks the fourth wall in Peter Pan and also plays God with the lives of the characters&amp;quot;. That&amp;#39;s an intriguing discussion. What does it mean for the narrator that he can decide to kill Skylights or decide to prolong the suffering of the Darling parents? Is Peter Pan real in his world and is he God? Or is Peter Pan just a story in his world?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But people seem to be more fond of posting &amp;quot;Just finished this book (my first in years!) and it was wonderful!&amp;quot; and proceeding to give a synopsis and gushing over it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/imnotthatguyiswear&quot;&gt; /u/imnotthatguyiswear &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gol44w/if_i_took_a_vodka_shot_for_every_time_i_saw_just/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gol44w/if_i_took_a_vodka_shot_for_every_time_i_saw_just/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gol44w</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gol44w/if_i_took_a_vodka_shot_for_every_time_i_saw_just/" /><updated>2020-05-22T15:11:30+00:00</updated><title>If I took a vodka shot for every time I saw &quot;Just finished reading So-and-So Book&quot; on this subreddit, I'd be drunk every single day.</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/realrealityreally</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/realrealityreally</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve read dozens of Stephen King books and know he can be hit or miss, but over all he&amp;#39;s usually worth the purchase. However, &amp;quot;The Outsider&amp;quot; made me wonder if he is either just cranking books out for the money or if he is losing some of his creative ability. I would like to list the specific reasons if anyone else is interested.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/realrealityreally&quot;&gt; /u/realrealityreally &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gokygq/just_finished_stephen_kings_the_outsider_is_king/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gokygq/just_finished_stephen_kings_the_outsider_is_king/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gokygq</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gokygq/just_finished_stephen_kings_the_outsider_is_king/" /><updated>2020-05-22T15:02:45+00:00</updated><title>Just finished Stephen King's &quot;The Outsider&quot;. Is King starting to lose his fast ball?</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/ilonajane</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/ilonajane</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi all, I&amp;#39;m just getting back into reading and usually I try to read through books on my bookshelf before buying more books but I&amp;#39;m feeling a bit uninspired by it&amp;#39;s choices at the moment. Usually I&amp;#39;d head down to my local charity shops to see what they have but of course I can&amp;#39;t do that in the current climate. I want to still buy books second hand to save my wallet and the planet a bit but struggling to find a good second hand book website. Can anyone recommend please?! ☺️📚&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;(Ps I&amp;#39;m UK based)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/ilonajane&quot;&gt; /u/ilonajane &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gojlya/second_hand_book_websites_suggestions_please/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gojlya/second_hand_book_websites_suggestions_please/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gojlya</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gojlya/second_hand_book_websites_suggestions_please/" /><updated>2020-05-22T13:44:46+00:00</updated><title>Second Hand Book websites - suggestions please!</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/Rock_Blocker</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/Rock_Blocker</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just finished it for the first time and i can see why its a classic, very smart and all. The first two parts i enjoyed it. I was intrigued from the get go by the developing world and the realistic protagonist we got. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I liked how the story unfolded through the two parts and even enjoyed the twist about O&amp;#39;Brien... But part 3 i just found incredibly boring, it was well written and made you think but i was so bored by it, i ended up jumping paragraphs at a time. I thought it was a very solid ending though.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyone else feel the same way about it?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/Rock_Blocker&quot;&gt; /u/Rock_Blocker &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golwcz/anyone_else_found_1984_kinda_boring/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golwcz/anyone_else_found_1984_kinda_boring/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_golwcz</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golwcz/anyone_else_found_1984_kinda_boring/" /><updated>2020-05-22T15:55:18+00:00</updated><title>Anyone else found 1984 kinda.... Boring?</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/SoUdontKnowWhoIam</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/SoUdontKnowWhoIam</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know this book has been covered a million times, to the point where there’s a circlejerk about people circlejerking to 1984. I thought that was funny as I’ve been trying to find the answer to this... how ironic. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But here’s my question:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I understand that the motives for the government to control in the end is strictly for power. What I’m not wrapping my head around is why? Why would you want power strictly to enslave man to gain more power? What’s the end goal here? It seems like it’s just a really sadistic government that just wants to rule so it can oppress people which in turn gets more power. I’d get it more for the materialistic part... so is it just Orwell showing that a government COULD be like this? Or is there something else behind that? And yes, I know this isn’t the main message to the book, but I’d like some opinions. This seems like really breaking it down into the “metas” but I just would like to understand.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;TLDR: Why is the government oppressing strictly for the sake of power and nothing else?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/SoUdontKnowWhoIam&quot;&gt; /u/SoUdontKnowWhoIam &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok2fs/1984_question/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok2fs/1984_question/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gok2fs</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok2fs/1984_question/" /><updated>2020-05-22T14:12:02+00:00</updated><title>1984 question</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/Landmedlagbyggas</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/Landmedlagbyggas</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know if it&amp;#39;s about me lacking imagination or if my mind is too lazy to comprehend certain subjects. I find it&amp;#39;s oftentimes pretty easy to imagine people and creatures in books and give them a definitive face, but i struggle a lot with imagining structures in books.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example i read a book series which revolved around one character being a construction engineer for a bridge in the Norwegian mountains. I hated these chapters because i never got the layout of the location they were always at, at which stage in the process of construction they were at or how it even looked when it was finished.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I find that movies based on books really help me out with this. I read the Harry Potter series after seeing a few of the movies and i felt as though the movies really helped me out to imagine Hogwarts in the &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; way. If my own imagination were up to it, it would look more like the Tower of London or something else way off.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyone else have this conundrum? Maybe i just need to be more attentive when it comes to descriptions of environments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/Landmedlagbyggas&quot;&gt; /u/Landmedlagbyggas &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gog70n/problems_with_imagining_certain_things_in_books/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gog70n/problems_with_imagining_certain_things_in_books/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gog70n</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gog70n/problems_with_imagining_certain_things_in_books/" /><updated>2020-05-22T09:32:20+00:00</updated><title>Problems with imagining certain things in books?</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/NotSuitable4Humans</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/NotSuitable4Humans</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This may be a strange post.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I have always had a problem reading a book. Not to say that I&amp;#39;m illiterate by any means, I&amp;#39;m not - but I&amp;#39;ve always had a hard time sticking to a novel. Funny enough, I LOVE books. I love the idea of having a nearly infinite amount of words to visit, mysteries to solve, the feel of one in my hand, the smell. But I have always had a hard time focusing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This has been me for as long as I remember, and I think the last book I actually finished all the way through was the &lt;em&gt;Hunger Games&lt;/em&gt;, a week before the first movie came out in theaters. When I read a book, no matter the time of day, the weather or how I&amp;#39;m feeling, I fall asleep. I&amp;#39;ve had people respond to me, &amp;quot;Well, it if was good/exciting, then you wouldn&amp;#39;t be able to put it down&amp;quot;, but that&amp;#39;s not the case for me. I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; really enjoying &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;7 1/2 deaths of Evelyn Hardcastle&lt;/em&gt; but I doze off constantly. To put it in perspective the best I can, I have done many things over the years to try to pep up before opening a book. To drinking an energy drink or coffee prior/during and probably the most silly, sitting outside on a Summer day so I couldn&amp;#39;t possibly sleep to read. Spoiler Alert: &lt;span class=&quot;md-spoiler-text&quot;&gt;I feel asleep sitting outside in the middle of Summer trying to read a book. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Does anyone else at all do this? I haven&amp;#39;t ever met another person face-to-face who has, but maybe on Reddit? It&amp;#39;s always been the hardest thing for me to do, but hell, I still buy books because I want to read so many of them. If anyone has any suggestions or experiences with something similar, I&amp;#39;d love to hear it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Funny enough, all the above is the product of what happens when I actually make time to read a book. My brain is all over the place usually and instead of reading, I&amp;#39;ll go to watching videos or playing a game, or just about anything else - but I think a lot of that is because I know if I do, I&amp;#39;ll just fall asleep and I don&amp;#39;t want to take a nap. There are at least 40 books in my collection that I want to read, some that I&amp;#39;ve owned for years, but I just can&amp;#39;t get through them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyways, thanks in advance, Reddit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/NotSuitable4Humans&quot;&gt; /u/NotSuitable4Humans &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gombby/ive_always_had_difficulty_reading_a_query/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gombby/ive_always_had_difficulty_reading_a_query/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gombby</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gombby/ive_always_had_difficulty_reading_a_query/" /><updated>2020-05-22T16:17:05+00:00</updated><title>I've Always Had Difficulty Reading (A Query)</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/youwhoyouhoo</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/youwhoyouhoo</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel like many of us read books we think we &amp;quot;should&amp;quot; read (&amp;quot;classics&amp;quot;), as well as books we simply want to be entertained by.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I would include contemporary classics here by the way, anything you might read out of a sense of intellectual obligation/curiosity rather than entertainment alone.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/youwhoyouhoo&quot;&gt; /u/youwhoyouhoo &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goma8y/what_classic_turned_out_to_be_a_surprisingly/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goma8y/what_classic_turned_out_to_be_a_surprisingly/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_goma8y</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goma8y/what_classic_turned_out_to_be_a_surprisingly/" /><updated>2020-05-22T16:15:31+00:00</updated><title>What &quot;classic&quot; turned out to be a surprisingly light or entertaining read for you?</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/uselessfoster</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/uselessfoster</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m re-reading Ethan Frome for the first time since high school and it is...still boring. I thought I’d give it another chance because I recently read (and liked) House of Mirth and all her ghost stories (in fact, I just finished teaching a class about EW’s ghost stories) but Ethan Frome is mostly a book about things not happening set in a place that that is best known for being boring. The first framing chapter is also long and (a little) mysterious but mostly disorienting. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Look, I’m appreciating this book more than I did as a 10th-grader, but I can’t understand why some adult would think “this. This is what 15-year-olds need.” How many 15-year-olds have pressing interests about will-they-won’t-they adultary? It’s not even the best short work by Edith Wharton!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;/rant&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/uselessfoster&quot;&gt; /u/uselessfoster &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gom3s5/someone_give_me_a_good_argument_of_why_ethan/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gom3s5/someone_give_me_a_good_argument_of_why_ethan/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gom3s5</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gom3s5/someone_give_me_a_good_argument_of_why_ethan/" /><updated>2020-05-22T16:06:01+00:00</updated><title>Someone give me a good argument of why Ethan Frome is a sophomore literature text.</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/leowr</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/leowr</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: There is nothing wrong with Harry Mulisch and his books, but when thinking of Dutch literature he tends to be one of the names that comes up fairly quickly and The Assault is definitely one of the books that get picked a lot of school assigned reading. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I&amp;#39;ve done one of these (you can find links to the previous ones below), so I figured it was time for another one. I have always had the impression that quite a large part of Dutch literature has themes that deal with World War II and its aftermath, but that could be a consequence of what was focused on in my surroundings. While it cannot be denied that WWII left a great impression on many well-known Dutch authors, there is quite a range of books out there that unfortunately don&amp;#39;t always end up translated. I just wanted to highlight a few that I enjoyed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15797938-the-dinner&quot;&gt;The Dinner&lt;/a&gt; by Herman Koch - This book was a big hit in the Netherlands and had quite a bit of buzz when it got translated into English. I can definitely see why. I would recommend that you go into the book knowing as little about the plot as possible, because figuring out what is going in is probably the best part of the whole book. All I will say that it is about a tense dinner with two brothers and their wives while they are trying to figure out what happened and how to deal with the consequences of &lt;em&gt;the event&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1232307.Out_of_Mind&quot;&gt;Out of Mind&lt;/a&gt; by J. Bernlef - I am surprised I liked this book as much as I did (my sister hated it), but that is perhaps because I have seen what Alzheimer&amp;#39;s can do a person and those who love them. The book is about Maarten Klein, a 71-year-old, who has Alzheimer&amp;#39;s. The book is told from his perspective and I found it heart wrenching to read how he was slowly losing grip on his life. I, as the reader, knew what was going on, what is doing to his wife, but also what the disease was doing to Maarten. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40537814-the-boy-between-worlds&quot;&gt;The Boy Between Worlds&lt;/a&gt; by Annejet van der Zijl - A nonfiction book about Waldemar Nods, a 19-year-old student that immigrated to the Netherlands from Suriname, and Rika van der Lans, a 40-year-old Dutch married mother of four. Rika ends up pregnant with a son, Waldy. When the second World War breaks out the family helps hide Jews from the Nazi, but they are found out and arrested. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16026493-paaz&quot;&gt;Paaz&lt;/a&gt; by Myrthe van der Meer - I apologize for including this one as it hasn&amp;#39;t been translated (yet), but I wanted to include it anyways. Paaz is about Emma, who has a good job, a great partner and an overall wonderful life. So she doesn&amp;#39;t see why the fact that she wants to die is such a problem. Emma ends up on the psychiatric ward where she makes unexpected friends, has to adjust to life with strict rules and figure out why she is there. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What are some your favorite Dutch authors (that aren&amp;#39;t named Harry Mulisch) and why do you like them? If you have read any of the books I mentioned, what did you think of them? What is your impression of Dutch literature in general?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;p.s. I have done some other posts like this. In case you want to check them out: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/efusqh/japanese_authors_that_arent_named_haruki_murakami/&quot;&gt;Japanese authors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/ers1ix/chinese_authors_that_arent_named_cixin_liu/&quot;&gt;Chinese authors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/faa60n/nigerian_authors_that_arent_named_chinua_achebe/&quot;&gt;Nigerian authors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/fglwkp/french_authors_that_arent_named_alexandre_dumas/&quot;&gt;French authors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/fsvhbk/italian_authors_that_arent_named_elena_ferrante/&quot;&gt;Italian authors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/leowr&quot;&gt; /u/leowr &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gom2fm/dutch_authors_that_arent_named_harry_mulisch/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gom2fm/dutch_authors_that_arent_named_harry_mulisch/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gom2fm</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gom2fm/dutch_authors_that_arent_named_harry_mulisch/" /><updated>2020-05-22T16:04:04+00:00</updated><title>Dutch Authors that aren't named Harry Mulisch</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/Creepy_Roll</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/Creepy_Roll</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golp8v/the_case_of_oscar_wildes_mistaken_identity_in/&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://b.thumbs.redditmedia.com/lE6_2PddBf-FATn96DIw_wcbddVuAGmbed0Ph937Uxo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Case of Oscar Wilde’s Mistaken Identity in Naples&quot; title=&quot;The Case of Oscar Wilde’s Mistaken Identity in Naples&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/Creepy_Roll&quot;&gt; /u/Creepy_Roll &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artbook.com/9788862087148.html&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golp8v/the_case_of_oscar_wildes_mistaken_identity_in/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</content><id>t3_golp8v</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golp8v/the_case_of_oscar_wildes_mistaken_identity_in/" /><updated>2020-05-22T15:44:18+00:00</updated><title>The Case of Oscar Wilde’s Mistaken Identity in Naples</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/LemonPepperTrout</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/LemonPepperTrout</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve never read this novella, it&amp;#39;s the story of a woman and her son who live in a future civilization which is entirely underground and have their every need met by a centralized machine. Everyone communicates through methods strongly resembling the internet and social media, music is streamed electronically, and air travel was once a dominant form of transportation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The crazy part? This story was published in 1909.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Knowing that, it astounded me how similarly the story read to our modern world. It&amp;#39;s positively filled with the shallow relationships and lack of social skills which plague our society (especially the line about the protagonist knowing thousands of people yet being reticent to visit her son face to face), and still being under quarantine, I could feel the weight of all those tiny cells stacked on on top another as I read. There&amp;#39;s also plenty of relevant moments regarding religious belief (and a stated lack thereof) in technological societies, disconnection with nature, and how technology affects human cognition.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That being said, I think this story overlooks the positive side of technological advancement (understandably, both being a dystopia and written at the dawn of the 20th century). While it is true that technology can isolate and people are prone to replace real relationships with Facebook likes and follower statistics, technology can also bring people together. During this quarantine, for instance, not only have I connected with friends through phone and internet, I&amp;#39;ve also made new connections on Discord and am able to play video games with people from Europe and India. Without the internet, I would&amp;#39;t have this book in my collection. With my library and nearby bookstores being closed, I relied on internet shopping to acquire new reading material.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think the real lesson to take away from any vision of the future, good or bad, is that it&amp;#39;s not the technology itself that is detrimental, but the way in which humans handle it, which Forster touches on as well. Will technology ultimately be mankind&amp;#39;s undoing? Possibly, but I don&amp;#39;t think so. Ultimately, if anything undoes humanity, it will be that we have undone ourselves.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/LemonPepperTrout&quot;&gt; /u/LemonPepperTrout &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goaa66/reading_em_forsters_the_machine_stops_in_the_age/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goaa66/reading_em_forsters_the_machine_stops_in_the_age/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_goaa66</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goaa66/reading_em_forsters_the_machine_stops_in_the_age/" /><updated>2020-05-22T01:54:06+00:00</updated><title>Reading E.M. Forster's &quot;The Machine Stops&quot; in the Age of Coronavirus</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/ParadoxFusion</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/ParadoxFusion</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jordan Peterson receives alot of underserved backlash and the stigma around him can put alot of people off the book. The truth is , this book is a coherent set of rules which if implemented , really can improve your life for the better . It is true that there were points where I found myself detracted by the repetitive Bible ramblings in the earlier rules. Not only this but his style of writing is much more academic than anything. However, once you look past the books faults , this is one of the few self help books that i can say actually helped me. Try to set aside your preconceptions on Peterson or , in the very least, conduct your own research into him before accepting other peoples opinions on him. This book deserves a chance in the very least , it may not help you like it did me , but it certainly can be thought provoking.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/ParadoxFusion&quot;&gt; /u/ParadoxFusion &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok0xr/just_finished_12_rules_for_life_here_are_my/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok0xr/just_finished_12_rules_for_life_here_are_my/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_gok0xr</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/gok0xr/just_finished_12_rules_for_life_here_are_my/" /><updated>2020-05-22T14:09:39+00:00</updated><title>Just finished 12 rules for life - here are my thoughts.</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/hindispeakingmallu</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/hindispeakingmallu</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was so different from books that i generally read, which is mostly thrillers or mystery but i read great reviews about this book, so thought to give it a try, I did start a few months back but didn&amp;#39;t feel interested after rhe first chapter, but now in this lockdown thought I&amp;#39;ll give it one more try and finished it in 3 days.. I wonder if in this fast paced world people still have such good neighborhood or even know their neighbors, I would like to live with neighbors like Ove and Parvenah. 100% recommended ❤❤❤&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/hindispeakingmallu&quot;&gt; /u/hindispeakingmallu &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/go2io6/just_finished_reading_a_man_called_ove_and_what/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/go2io6/just_finished_reading_a_man_called_ove_and_what/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_go2io6</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/go2io6/just_finished_reading_a_man_called_ove_and_what/" /><updated>2020-05-21T18:40:24+00:00</updated><title>Just finished reading A man called Ove and what can i say, after a long time read such a feel good book which made me teary eyed in between.</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/IfIWereMe2</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/IfIWereMe2</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I juste finished Pale Fire, my first book by Nabokov. This is undeniably an excellent book, the idea and execution are just incredible. But I was a little underwhelmed by the prose, it&amp;#39;s well-written, no doubt about it, but having heard that Nabokov have one of the best prose ever, it was a bit of a let-down.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Am I the only one to think that ? Are the other works by Nabokov differently written ?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/IfIWereMe2&quot;&gt; /u/IfIWereMe2 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goj1qt/pale_fire_prose/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goj1qt/pale_fire_prose/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_goj1qt</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goj1qt/pale_fire_prose/" /><updated>2020-05-22T13:08:51+00:00</updated><title>Pale Fire prose</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/badgalrocroc</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/badgalrocroc</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t know anyone that has read this book and I really need to vent how I feel. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are many things I wish I knew how to say about what this book has done to me. I have never cried reading a book. I have shed one or two tears a few times over my years and years of reading but never actually cried. This book had me borderline sobbing on multiple occasions. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I felt like Jude, Willem, JB, Malcom, Harold, and Andy were my closest, deepest friends. I longed to hold them individually and together at once. I felt like there was a piece of me in every single one them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was physically and mentally abused for the majority of my childhood. My earliest memories are getting beat by the hands of my mother’s boyfriend (we’ll call him V). I’m now 30 and still have a thin, two inch scar on the back of my head from when V picked me up and threw me against a bookshelf when I was three years old(one of many memories). I still remember how the color of my blood looked dripping from my head. It was a dark red, more maroon-like puddle on the back of my hand as I sat with my head hanging down in the bathroom while my mother and V argued about if I should go to the hospital or not. What felt like seconds later, I came-to in the hospital getting discharged the same evening after receiving stitches. I have never forgotten that memory but I can’t remember most of childhood birthdays. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My mother ended up having two children with V (five total, I’m number three). They have not been together in 20 years but he has still been in my life here and there because he is my younger siblings father (I am very close with my siblings). V has apologized to me many times over the years, which I have always accepted because I genuinely believe he is sorry. I have made my peace with V and my mother a long time ago but I have never made peace with my history. I have struggled with depression my whole life. I had years of alcohol abuse and a list of shitty, abusive ex-boyfriends that I stayed with too long because I thought I didn’t deserve better. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before I started this book, my daughter’s first birthday just happened. Ever since I had a baby, a lot of my childhood trauma has been resurfacing. I look at my daughter and I can’t fucking fathom how anyone can hurt a defenseless child, especially in their most crucial, vulnerable, an absorbent years. I started to resent V again. I honestly feel like I hate him, although I still forgive him because I truly believe he is not the same person he was back then. I feel like I let my child-self down by forgiving him so easily when I have cut people out of my life for lesser crimes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This book has shown me that I certainly need to give therapy a real chance. And that I also need to talk more about how I’m feeling. I have always felt damaged. I have always felt like there’s nothing I can do because I can’t change the past. I have always felt that being an adult is accepting that the damage is done, suck it up, and move on as best as you can. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have a handful of close friends that I’ve had for years, some of them since my teen years. One of them being the greatest person I have ever known. I have always wondered what I did to deserve her and how she could be friends with me. How she could still be friends with me after all those years of watching me put myself in dark holes. Watching me date abuser after abuser never fully understanding how I could do that to myself. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Willem reminded me of her in so many ways. His gentle spirit that attracts anyone and everyone around him. His knowing in what is wrong and right, but never putting Jude down for his uncontrollable darkness. His endless love, support, and loyalty to his friendship without even knowing Jude’s whole story.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is extremely rare when I read a book I’m into and not blow through it insanely fast. I took my time with this one and soaked in every word. I put it down for a few days because I needed it to last. I had six pages left and took another few days because I wasn’t ready to say goodbye. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I truly love this book. I am extremely grateful for this read and the hundreds of times I have seen the book suggested over different subs on reddit. I don’t know if I will ever be able to read it again but I know I will never forget how it made me feel from the first to last page. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have left a piece of me in this book and it will forever be a part of me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/badgalrocroc&quot;&gt; /u/badgalrocroc &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goef02/just_finished_a_little_life_by_hanya_yanagihara/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goef02/just_finished_a_little_life_by_hanya_yanagihara/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_goef02</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goef02/just_finished_a_little_life_by_hanya_yanagihara/" /><updated>2020-05-22T06:57:59+00:00</updated><title>Just finished A Little Life by Hanya Yanagihara</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/TheChumOfChance</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/TheChumOfChance</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was really resistant to anything old, but over the past few years I&amp;#39;ve been moving the date back on the books I&amp;#39;ve read (or bought at least), and I&amp;#39;ve been pleasantly surprised to see how wrong I was.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Gravity&amp;#39;s Rainbow is one of my favorite books, and a lot of people on &lt;a href=&quot;/r/ThomasPynchon&quot;&gt;r/ThomasPynchon&lt;/a&gt; agree that Moby Dick and Gravity&amp;#39;s Rainbow are very similar, so that&amp;#39;s what finally convinced me to read it. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m only about 90 pages in so far, so I don&amp;#39;t want any spoilers, but any hot takes or advice about the book? Thanks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/TheChumOfChance&quot;&gt; /u/TheChumOfChance &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goeq09/i_finally_broke_down_and_bought_a_copy_of_moby/&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goeq09/i_finally_broke_down_and_bought_a_copy_of_moby/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_goeq09</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/goeq09/i_finally_broke_down_and_bought_a_copy_of_moby/" /><updated>2020-05-22T07:24:22+00:00</updated><title>I finally broke down and bought a copy of Moby Dick. Any advice on what metaphors to look out for?</title></entry><entry><author><name>/u/InstantIdealism</name><uri>https://www.reddit.com/user/InstantIdealism</uri></author><category term="books" label="r/books"/><content type="html">&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/InstantIdealism&quot;&gt; /u/InstantIdealism &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irishtimes.com/culture/books/twenty-seven-year-old-irish-debut-novelist-signs-six-figure-deal-1.4259979?mode=amp&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR31bhBI8tmw-owsRvGEBgVcjK15_6tii7bGQLcW5Sd8H8cWqP0zS5bhFIw&quot;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golwiq/twentysevenyearold_irish_debut_novelist_signs/&quot;&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><id>t3_golwiq</id><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/books/comments/golwiq/twentysevenyearold_irish_debut_novelist_signs/" /><updated>2020-05-22T15:55:30+00:00</updated><title>Twenty-seven-year-old Irish debut novelist signs six-figure deal</title></entry></feed>